Muhammad Mahedi Hasan

Software Engineer

Section 2, Mirpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

in https://bd.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-mahedi-hasan-739bb6180

S live:mahadih727_1

https:/hackerrank.com/mahadih727



Skills

PHP • Javascript • OOP • LARAVEL VueJs • ReactJs • jQuery • MySQL

GIT • Docker • Linux

Interests

Web Development • Problem Solving Open Source Contribution • AWS **Kubernets**

Online Profile

HackerRank 17

https://hackerrank.com/mahadih727

Github 🗗

https://github.com/MuhammadMahediHas

Education

Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT)

B.Sc in CSE Sep 2019 - Aug 2023 Rupnagar, Mirpur, Dhaka.

Feni Computer Institute

Diploma in Engineering Sep 2015 - Jun 2019 | Feni, Bangladesh

Profile

A Dedicated and collaborative software professional with 4 years of experience. Experience in developing and maintaining large scale enterprise application. Highly experienced in **Backend/REST API** development in **Laravel**. Love to write **clean code** and follow best practices. And also have solid frontend development. Seeking an opportunity for the fulfillment of my passion for software engineering at a well established organization through an ongoing career.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer

SkylarkSoft Limited

Aug 2021 - present | Mirpur DOHS, Dhaka

- Tech Stack PHP, Laravel, VueJS, ReactJs, jQuery.
- Develop and contribute on **goRMG ERP** several modules and features such as Knitting, Yarn store, Time and action, HR and Planning.
- Contributed on production tracking (**ProTracker**) system development and Developed several complex reports.
- Contribute on mail system for daily reports from Protracker, Merchandising and Commercial at user defined schedule.
- Build notification system for remind users of their task.
- Optimized System with efficient use of Laravel queues, scheduling and improve query performance that makes application faster and smooth.
- Implement design patterns for reusable, maintainable, readable and developer friendly codebase.
- Collaborate to built several private Laravel packages.
- Implement third party device API for managing employee attendance.
- Practices Domain Driven Development.
- Working experience on **docker** environment.
- Have some working experience with **Linux** server.
- Participated knowledge sharing session with team.
- Collaborated with OA team

Software Engineer

Expert IT Solution

Jul 2020 - Jul 2021 | kallyanpur, Dhaka

Tech Stack - PHP, Laravel, VueJS

- Contributed on several application development, improvement and acting as a team leader.
- **prominentedu.com** 🗹 : a online course selling and quiz system. Requirement analysis, develop, maintain and implement the system.
- Inventory Management Software: Contributes on several modules.
- **bhorerkagojprokashan.com** 🗷 : Develop e-commerce application. Which is based on Laravel and VueJs.

Internship/Jr. Software Engineer

TMSS ICT Limited

Jun 2019 – Jun 2020 | Kazipara, Mirpur, Dhaka

Tech Stack - PHP, Laravel, VueJS, ¡Query

- School Management ERP: Developed and maintain several modules.
- Developed ISP management application.
- Developed Point of Sale (POS) system for tracking inventory, stock and sale's.

Muhammad Mahedi Hasan 1/1